[音乐] 在这第一节关于 http
[Music]
in this first section on http we're going to start off with just a
我们将首先快速概述 Web 和 http
very quick overview of the web and http
然后我们将深入研究两种类型的 http 连接
then we're going to dive down into the
two types of http connections
持久和非持久连接以及
persistent and non-persistent
connections and
查看http使用的主要消息请求消息和响应
look at the major messages used by http
the request message and the response
消息然后最后我们将首先结束这个
message and then finally we'll wrap up
this first
部分通过查看所谓的 cookie 的一种方式
section by taking a look at what are
known as cookies a ways for
在一个客户端连接之间在服务器上持久化的状态
state to persist at a server between one
client connection
和另一个客户端连接现在这只是第一个
and another client connection now this  just the first
is just the first
我们将在 http 中介绍的两部分
of two parts that we're going to cover on http but we've got a
但我们这里有很多内容要讲，让我们开始吧
lot to cover here so let's get started well let's begin our discussion of
好吧，让我们以非常快速的方式开始我们对 Web 和 http 的讨论
the web and http with just a very quick review to set the stage
审查以设置舞台 请记住，一个网页由一个
remember that a web page consists of a
基本 html 文件以及一组引用
base
html file as well as a set of referenced
对象，并且这些对象中的每一个都可以存储在不同的 Web 服务器上
objects and each of these objects can be
stored on different web servers
一个对象可以是一个 html 文件 jpeg 图像一个 java 苹果
an object can be an html file jpeg image
a java apple
音频文件或许多其他东西和网页本身以及参考
audio file or many other things and the
web page itself as well as the reference
每个对象都可以通过所谓的 url 寻址
objects are each addressable by what's
known as a url
有一个与之关联的主机名，然后在该主机上有一个路径
there's a host name associated with it
and then on that host there's a path
给它起个名字让我们开始我们的研究
name piece to it
well let's get started with our study of
http 并且首先要知道的是 http 采用客户端服务器
http and the very first thing to know
is that http adopts the client server
我们刚刚在 2.1 节中研究的模型
model that we just studied in section
2.1
客户端可能是像 firefox 或 safari 这样的网络浏览器，或者
a client might be a web browser like
firefox or safari or
边缘，或者它实际上可能嵌入在设备中，您甚至可能看不到它
edge or it might actually be embedded in
a device and you might not even see it
服务器可能是传统的 Web 服务器
a server might be a traditional web
server that
仅提供网页或更通用的服务器
only serves web pages or a more general
purpose server
像 gaia.cs.umass.edu 提供了许多服务
like gaia.cs.umass.edu which provides a
number of services
在此动画中，我们看到在运行 Firefox 浏览器的顶级 PC 上
in this animation here we see on the top
pc running the firefox browser
向服务器发出 http 请求并获得响应
making an http request to a server and
getting a response
回到底部，我们看到运行 safari 浏览器的 iphone 也在制作一个
back at the bottom we see an iphone
running safari browser also making an
http 请求并得到一个 http 响应
http request
and getting an http response back both
这些浏览器中的一个与 apache 网络服务器使用 http 协议
of those browsers are speaking the http
protocol with the apache web server
http使用tcp提供的传输服务
http uses the transport services
provided by the tcp
协议以及 http 事务的工作原理
protocol and here's how an http
transaction works
例如，您的网络浏览器的 http 客户端
the http client your web browser for
example
使用端口 80 打开到 Web 服务器的 tcp 连接。我们将了解端口
opens a tcp connection to a web server
using port 80. we'll learn about port
一秒或多条消息 http 消息中的数字
numbers in just a second
one or more messages http messages are
然后在客户端和服务器之间交换
then exchanged between the client and
the server
然后tcp连接关闭http是无状态协议
and then the tcp connection is closed
http is a stateless protocol
这意味着服务器不维护正在进行的请求的内部状态
this means that the server maintains no
internal state about the ongoing request
有一个对象的单一请求和一个单一的答复就是这样
there's a single request for an object
and a single reply that's it
不用担心这个交易有五个步骤
there's no worrying about something like
well this transaction has five steps
我们现在在第三步，如果我失败了，我将需要滚动
we're now in step three
and if i fail i'm going to need to roll
将我的状态恢复到这五步交易之前的状态
back my state to what it was
before this five step transaction
开始时没有使用 http 它是无状态的，您可能会问为什么
started none of that with http
it's stateless and you might ask why
很好，因为它很简单，因为我们将看到维护
well because of its simplicity
as we'll see protocols that maintain
state 需要处理多步事务时的清理问题
state will need to deal with clean up
problems when a multi-step transaction
无法返回初始状态并且
fails
returning to the initial state and
解决不一致的状态有两种类型的 http 连接
resolving inconsistent state
there are two types of http connections
什么叫做持久连接和非持久连接，它是
what are called persistent connections
and non-persistent connections and it's
记住浏览器之间的这些 http 连接很重要
important to remember
these http connections between a browser
并且服务器与提供的 tcp 连接不同
and a server are different than the tcp
connection which is provided at the
非持久性 http 下的传输层 tcp 连接
transport layer underneath
in non-persistent http a tcp connection
最多打开一个对象，然后通过
is opened
at most one object is then sent over the
tcp 连接，tcp 连接关闭
tcp connection
and the tcp connection is closed
下载多个对象将需要多个 tcp
downloading multiple
objects is going to require multiple tcp
建立连接，我们将看到它需要往返
connections to be established
and we'll see that it takes a round-trip
时间先打开tcp连接然后另一个rtt
time first to open the tcp connection
and then another rtt
发出请求并接收响应
to make the request and receive the
response
在持久的 http 中，tcp 连接再次向服务器开放
in persistent http a tcp connection is
again open to the server
但是这次可以传输多个对象
but this time multiple objects can be
transferred
通过客户端之间的单个 tcp 连接串行
serially over the single tcp connection
between the client
一旦这些多个对象被请求并返回服务器
and the server once those multiple
objects have been requested and returned
tcp连接可以关闭持久http对应http
the tcp connection can be closed
persistent http corresponds to http
1.1 版，这可能是当今使用的最常见的 http 形式
version 1.1 which is probably the most
common form of http in use today
这是非持久性 http 和操作的示例
here's an example of non-persistent http
and operation
让我们假设用户在步骤 1a 中输入了一个 url
let's assume that the user in step 1a
here enters a url
www.sumschool.edu 并要求提供包含
www.sumschool.edu
and asks for a web page that contains text as well as references to
文本以及对该基本 html 文件中的 10 个 jpeg 图像的引用
10 jpeg image in that base html file
所以在步骤 1a 中，我们看到客户端启动了到
so in step 1a we see the client
initiating the tcp connection to the
http 服务器位于 www.sumschool.edu 的 80 端口
http server
at port 80 at www.sumschool.edu
在步骤 1b 中，主机上的 http 服务器一直在等待 tcp
in step 1b the http server at the host
which has been waiting for a tcp
端口 80 上的连接接受此 tcp 连接
connection at port 80 accepts this tcp
connection
并在步骤一 a 和一 b 中通知客户和通知
and notifies the client and notice in
steps one a and one b
还没有真正的 http 请求流过
no http requests have actually flowed
yet
这发生在第二步中的第二步 http 客户端
this happens in step two in step two the
http client
将 http 请求消息发送到刚刚建立的 tcp 连接中
sends the http request message into the
tcp connection that's just been
建立这个http消息表明
established
this http message indicates that the
客户希望在步骤 3 中接收此基本 html 文件
client wants to receive
this base html file in step 3 the
服务器现在收到此 http 请求消息
servers now receive this http request
message
并形成包含请求对象的响应消息
and forms the response message that
contains the requested object
并将此消息发送回 http 客户端
and sends this message back to the http
client
在步骤 4 中发送响应消息后，http 服务器关闭 tcp
after sending the response message in
step 4 the http server closes the tcp
步骤 5 中的连接 http 客户端收到
connection
in step 5 the http client receives the
包含 html 文件的响应消息
response message containing the html
file
显示 html 文件解析它找到 10 个引用
displays the html file parses it finds
the 10 reference
jpeg 对象，现在在步骤 6 中将不得不重复
jpeg objects and in step 6 now
it's going to have to repeat the
每个参考 jpeg 对象的前五个步骤
preceding five steps
for each of the reference jpeg objects
现在我们可以看看非持久化http的响应时间
now we can take a look at the response
time for non-persistent http
我们可以将响应时间定义为从用户
we can define the response time as the
amount of time from when a user
首先在浏览器中输入一个 url，直到接收到该基本 html 文件
first enters a url into a browser
until that base html file is received
并显示所以让我们定义往返的 rtt
and displayed
so let's define the rtt the round trip
时间是一个非常小的数据包传播所需的时间
time as the amount of time
needed for a very small packet to travel
从客户端到服务器再返回 所以我们可以看到
from the client
to the server and back and so we can see
每个对象的非持久性 http 响应时间具有
that the non-persistent
http response time per object has the
以下组件需要一个 rtt 来启动
following components
well one rtt is needed to initiate the
tcp 连接和另一个 rtt 需要第二个 rtt
tcp connection
and another rtt a second rtt is needed
用于发送和接收http请求
for the http request to be transmitted
and received
以及 http 响应的第一个字节
and for the first bytes of the http
response
返回，然后终于有时间
to be returned and then finally there's
the amount of time
服务器实际传输文件所需的
needed for the server to actually
transmit the file
进入其互联网连接
into its internet connection
所以总的来说非持久性http响应时间
and so overall the non-persistent http
response time is two rtt plus whatever amount of time is needed to transmit
是两个 rtt 加上传输文件所需的任何时间
所以我们已经看到需要两个 rtts
the file so we've seen that two rtts are needed to fetch a web
获取一个 Web 对象现在通常可以并行检索多个对象，但是
object now multiple objects can often be retrieved in parallel but still two rtts
仍然是两个 rtts 是两个 rtts，你知道
is well two rtts and you know
two rtts is well two rtts and you know
我们真的想尽快获得我们的信息，所以这是可能的
we really want to get our information as fast as possible so it's possible
使用一种简单的技术将延迟从两个 rtt 减少到一个
using a simple technique to actually cut this latency from two rtts to one
rtt，那就是使用一种称为
rtt and that's to use a technique known as persistent connection and this is
持久连接，这是大多数网络的方式
服务器现在在持久性 http http 1.1 中运行
the way that most web servers are now operating in persistent http http 1.1
服务器在发送响应后保持连接打开
the server leaves the connection open after sending the response subsequent http messages between
然后可以发送同一客户端和服务器之间的后续 http 消息
the same client and server can then be sent over this open connection without
通过这个打开的连接而不必等待
当客户端有新的请求要发送时，rtt 建立新的 tcp 连接
having to wait that rtt to establish a new tcp connection when a client
它在遇到引用的对象时立即发送它，因此我们可以看到
has a new request to send it sends it as soon as it encounters
a referenced object and so we can see
在这里，持久性 http 如何缩短响应时间
here how persistent http cuts the
response time
现在我们已经看过这两种风格了
in half to one rdt
now that we've looked at the two styles
我们可以深入了解 http 连接的详细信息
of http connections we can dive down
into the details
http 消息本身并记住
of the http messages themselves and
remember
早在 1.1 节我们说过协议定义了格式和
way back in section 1.1 we said that a
protocol defines the format and the
之间发送和接收消息的顺序
order
of messages sent and received among
网络实体以及在这些情况下采取的行动
network entities
and the actions taken when these
消息的发送和接收 我们来看看http协议
messages are sent and received
let's take a look at the http protocol
我们来看看它的消息有两种类型的http消息
and let's take a look at its messages
there are two types of http messages
请求消息和响应消息让我们看一下请求消息
request messages and response messages
let's take a look at a request message
首先，请求消息以单个请求行开头
first a request message
starts with a single request line with
例如，以方法名称开头的那一行
that line beginning with a method name
for example
在这种情况下，获取此处显示的 url 请求的 html 文件的名称
get as shown here a url in this case the
name of the html file being requested
在这种情况下 http 的版本 1.1 和一个作为回车符的新行
the version of http in this case 1.1
and a new line that is a carriage return
换行然后跟随单个请求行
line feed
the single request line is then followed
通过许多提供附加信息的标题行
by a number of header lines that provide
additional information
例如发出请求的主机的名称
for example the name of the host where
the request is being made
在这种情况下发出请求的浏览器类型 firefox
the type of browser making a request in
this case firefox
可以接受的对象类型和首选语言
the types of objects that can be
accepted and preferred language in this
案例我们英语和事实，这
case u.s
english and the fact that this
连接应该保持活动状态请求消息以空结尾
connection should be kept alive
the request message ends with an empty
行，以便您可以看到非常可读的
line so as you can see
very human readable
这是 http 请求消息的一般格式
here's the general format for an http
request message
我们看到请求行后跟头行 http 协议规范
we see the request line followed by
header lines http protocol specification
rfc 7320 长达 85 页，包含有关
rfc 7320 is 85 pages long
and has all the details about the
幸运的是，作为网络的我们的方法头字段名称和值
methods header field names and values
fortunately for us as networking
学生，我们不需要知道所有这些细节，但如果我们知道
students we don't need to know
all of those details but if we were
实现我们必须知道的 http 客户端或服务器
implementing an http client or server
we'd have to know
当我们查看上一张幻灯片中的 get 消息时，每个细节都有
every detail when we looked at the get
message in the previous slide there was
某些请求消息不需要实体主体
no entity body
that's needed by some request messages
就像我们稍后会看到的需要发送附加信息的帖子
like post which we'll see in a second
that need to send additional information
不在服务器的头字段中，这里是四种类型的 http 请求
not in the header fields to the server
here are the four types of http request
消息我们已经看到了 get 方法 post 方法已经用于
messages we've seen the get method
already the post method is used to
将完成的表单数据上传到服务器，可以使用put方法上传
upload completed form data to the server
and the put method can be used to upload
具有给定 url 的服务器的新对象可能会替换
a new object to the server
with a given url possibly replacing an
现有对象和最后一个 head 方法要求一个
existing object
and last the head method ask for a
与 get 请求相同的响应，但
response that's
identical to that of a get request but
没有响应主体，这可以用于例如
without the response body
this could be used for example to
确定将要检索的对象的大小
determine the size of an object that
would be retrieved
但没有实际检索该对象
but without actually retrieving that
object
现在让我们快速看一下http响应消息 以状态行和状态行上的第一件事开始
now let's quickly take a look at the
http response message
现在让我们快速看一下http响应消息 以状态行和状态行上的第一件事开始
the response message begins with a
status line and the first thing on the
状态行是 http 的版本号
status line
is the version number of the http
本例中使用的协议在这里 1.1 遵循
protocol being used
in this example here 1.1 following the
版本号是两个最重要的信息
version number are the two most
important pieces of information
在响应消息中包含状态代码和短消息
in the response message a status code
and a short message
在这种情况下，显示的状态代码是 200，这意味着一切都进行了
in this case the status code shown is
200 which means that everything went
好的，在这种情况下是一个简短的状态短语
okay and a short status phrase in this
case
状态行后面的单词 ok 有响应标题行
the word ok following the status line
there are response header lines
就像提供附加信息的请求消息一样
as in the case of the request message
that provide additional information
例如，此处显示您可以看到发送响应的日期和时间
for example shown here you can see that
the date and time the response was sent
在这种情况下，服务器的类型也显示为 apache 服务器版本
the type of server is also shown in this
case an apache server version
2.4.6 last modified字段显示文档最后一次修改的时间
2.4.6 the last modified field shows the
time when the document was last modified
内容长度字段显示文档的长度
the content length field shows how long
the document is
并且内容类型字段指示正在返回的对象的类型
and the content type field indicates the
type of object that's being returned
在这种情况下是一个 html 文档，最后是对象的主体
in this case an html document and
finally the body of the object
在这种情况下返回 html 文档本身
being returned in this case the html
document itself
这里只是一些 http 响应状态代码和短语
and here are just a few of the http
response status codes and phrases
我们已经看到 200 OK 表示请求成功
we've already seen the 200 okay
indicating that a request has succeeded
您可能已经在请求文档时看到 404 not found
you've probably seen a 404 not found
when a requested document
在服务器上未找到所有响应状态代码和短语
was not found on the server all of the
response status codes and phrases are
包含在 rfc 文档中，所以看看那里
contained
in the rfc document so take a look there
如果你真的有兴趣了解所有
if you're
really interested in learning about all
状态代码和响应短语，这样我们对 http 的讨论就结束了
of the status codes and response phrases
so that wraps up our discussion of http
消息很简单，正如承诺的那样
messages
it's pretty simple as promised and
只有两种类型的消息，而且正如承诺的那样，它非常人性化
there's only two types of messages
and as also promised it's pretty human
易消化，我们可以查看那些 http 消息
digestible we could look at those http
messages
并且非常了解它们 让我们结束对 http 的初步研究
and pretty much understand them let's
wrap up our initial study of http
回到这个无国籍问题，我们说 http
by coming back to this question of
statelessness we said that http
是一种无状态协议，因为事实证明 Web 服务器可以
is a stateless protocol as it turns out
it's possible for a web server to
实际上维护一些用户状态以记住用户在
actually maintain some user state
to remember what a user's done in the
过去以及这可能如何影响用户
past
and how that might influence what a user
想要在当前会话中使用一种称为 cookie 的技术来完成
wants to do in a current session
by using a technique known as cookies
我们来看看网站会使用cookies来维护
let's take a look
websites will use cookies to maintain
有关用户的信息，更具体地说是用户的浏览器
information about a user
more specifically a user's browser in
在交易之间，有四个组件可以使用
between transactions
and there are four components to using
cookie 首先是某个服务器将要发送的
cookies first
a server at some point is going to send
给客户端的 cookie cookie 只是一个数字
a cookie
to a client the cookie is just a number
它包含在 cookie 标题行中
and it's contained in a cookie header
line
发送到客户端的 http 响应消息
of an http response message being sent
to a client
然后当客户端下次向该服务器发出请求时，它将
then later when the client next makes a
request to that server it will
在 cookie 标题行中将该 cookie 值发送到服务器
send along that cookie value to the
server in a cookie header line
现在服务器将记住所有收到的请求和
now the server is going to remember all
of the requests that's received and the
它发送的响应与该 cookie 值相关联，因此
responses it's sent
associated with that cookie value so
它将有与该用户交互的历史记录，让我们
it'll have a history
of the interactions with that user let's
看一个例子 让我们来看看这个例子
take a look at an example
let's take a look at an example in this
例如，左侧的客户端将发出几个 http 请求
example a client on the left here is
going to make a couple of http requests
例如到右侧的亚马逊服务器
to an amazon server for example on the
right
它有一个后端数据库，用于存储与 cookie 相关的
which has a back-end database where it's
going to store cookie-related
信息客户端也有cookie信息
information
the client also has cookie information
从其他网站访问它在这种情况下来自 ebay 的 cookie
from other websites it's visited
in this case a cookie from ebay for
示例但它没有来自亚马逊的 cookie
example but it doesn't have a cookie
from amazon
但是客户端最初像往常一样向亚马逊网络服务器发出请求
yet the client makes a request as usual
to the amazon web server initially
没有 cookie 行，当亚马逊网络服务器获得
without a cookie
line when the amazon web server gets the
http 请求创建一个 cookie 存储 cookie 和
http request
creates a cookie stores the cookie and
其数据库中的交易信息并发送
the transaction
information in its database and sends an
对客户端的 http 响应，包括 cookie 值
http response to the client
including a cookie value
现在在客户端的第二个请求中，客户端包含其 cookie
now here in the second request by the
client the client includes its cookie
亚马逊的价值允许亚马逊服务器采取
value to amazon
allowing the amazon server to take a
cookie 特定的操作可能采取第一个 http 请求
cookie specific action
perhaps taking the first http request
现在考虑例如可能是第一笔交易
now into account
for example maybe the first transaction
是查看一件商品的请求和第二个 http 请求
was a request to look at one item of
merchandise and the second http request
想看第二件商品
wanted to look at a second item of
merchandise
使用 cookie 可以制作第二个回复以向客户提供交易
with cookies the second reply could be
crafted to offer the client a deal on
购买这两种商品
buying
both of those items of merchandise
在一起，即使只有第二个请求
together
even though the second request only
想看看客户来的一件特定的商品
wanted to look at one particular
piece of merchandise the client comes
一周后回来又提供了一个cookie
back a week later and again provides a
cookie
服务器可以再次采取特定于 cookie 的操作
the server can again take a cookie
specific action
例如，它可以说嘿，我在过去一周想念你，你确定你
for example it could say hey i missed
you during the past week you sure you
不想买那些你过去看过的东西
don't want to buy those
items that you looked at during the past
周 所以在这个例子中我们可以看到如何
week
so in this example we can see how
cookie 可用于在网站上存储有关用户的状态
cookies can be used
to store state about a user at a website
鉴于 cookie 可用于存储在 http 交互之间
in between http interactions
given that cookies can be used to store
多个交易的用户状态，他们有很多用途记住
user state over multiple transactions
they've got lots of uses remembering
您之前已向网站验证过自己的身份
that you've authenticated yourself to a
site before
记住购物车的内容或制作
for remembering the contents of your
shopping cart or for making
基于过去行为的建议，您可能也有
recommendations
based on past behavior you may have also
阅读有关 cookie 的许多隐私问题
read about the many privacy concerns
about cookies  can allow websites to learn a
cookie 可以让网站了解很多关于你的信息
cookies can allow websites to learn a
lot about you there are what are called third-party cookies that can be put
有所谓的第三方 cookie 可以放入您的
浏览器并允许网站建立一个共同的
lot about you there are what are called third-party cookies that can be put
into your browser and allow websites to establish a common identity across multiple websites
跨多个网站的身份，您可能还拥有
听说了欧盟的一般数据保护法规 gdpr
and you may have also heard about the eu's general data protection regulation gdpr
在 gdpr cookie 下，对于网站的运营并非绝对必要
under gdpr cookies that aren't strictly necessary for the operation of a website can
只有在您明确同意后才能激活
only be activated after you've given your explicit consent for their use and for
供他们使用和收集个人数据
您最近可能已经注意到，在您能够使用之前，在很多网站上
the collection of personal data you may have noticed recently that at a lot
of sites before you're able to use
您最近可能已经注意到，在您能够使用之前，在很多网站上
lot of sites before you're able to use
该网站您必须同意某个 cookie 政策
that site you have to agree  to a certain cookie policy
好了，我们对网络的研究的第一部分就到此结束了
well that wraps up the first part of our
study of the web and http and we've learned a lot already we after
和 http ，我们已经学到了很多东西，我们在快速介绍之后
深入研究我们研究的不同类型的 http 连接
a quick introduction we dove down into the different types of http connections we
请求和响应消息，我们还以一种方式查看了 cookie
studied the request and the response messages and we also took a look at
记住用户之间服务器端的一些状态
cookies a way to remember some state on the server side between user interactions
与该服务器的交互，所以接下来在第二部分
with that server so coming up next in the second part we're going to
我们将进一步深入探讨
take another deeper dive into some additional aspects of improving http performance we're going
提高我们将要研究的 http 性能
Web 缓存我们将查看有条件的
take another deeper dive into some additional aspects of improving http performance we're going
to look at web caches we're going to look at the conditional get request
获取请求，最后我们将查看 http 版本 2
and then finally we're going to look at http version 2 the most recent
最新版本的 http 并快速浏览一下 http 版本 3
version of http and take a quick peek at http version 3  which is coming within the next year or
将在明年或
[音乐]
version of http and take a quick peek at http version 3  which is coming within the next year or
所以 你